<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kevin Shum</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/</link><description>Recent content on Kevin Shum</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Kevin Shum, &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Base Theme&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 23:27:59 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevinshum.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WFH: Ministry of Supply</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/wfh-ministry-of-supply/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/wfh-ministry-of-supply/</guid><description>Ministry of Supply started from MIT as a venture to infuse the latest technologies and research to design more performant and comfortable clothing. One of the cofounders ran a marathon in one of their suits. I&amp;rsquo;ve even skated, competed, and performed in their Apollo Dress Shirt and a pair of the Kinetic Pants. The stretch is perfect. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to try them out at a store to feel what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.</description></item><item><title>WFH: Space Monitor</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/wfh-space-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/wfh-space-monitor/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working-from-home for almost a month, and have been working off my company 13&amp;rdquo; laptop. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure how I lasted that long.
I finally gave in and bought a 27&amp;rdquo; Space Monitor. It arrived a a few days later. I chose this one because it had thin bezels, minimal advertising, and a space saving feature in which the stand clips and mounts to the edge of the desk.</description></item><item><title>WFH: Quarantine Cooking</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/wfh-quarantine-cooking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/wfh-quarantine-cooking/</guid><description>We got this, Seattle.
The weather has warmed up considerably. It&amp;rsquo;s been a nice change of pace. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t rained in a while and the sun is out more often than not. The seasons are changing quickly. It just makes it that much harder to stay indoors, but we need to all do our part in staying indoors as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;ve been cooking all my meals, and have more time to try new recipes and dishes.</description></item><item><title>Real Estate Agent</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/real-estate-agent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/real-estate-agent/</guid><description>Passing the Washington Real Estate Exam in 50 Days Some of my earliest memories was sitting with my mom scrolling through new homes on the market online. Each of us would take turns guessing the listing price based off the photos, location, and description. Sometimes she&amp;rsquo;d get it right, other times I would.
Ever since, I&amp;rsquo;ve been keen on real estate as a strategic investment opportunity. In fact, it helped fund my college tuition payments.</description></item><item><title>Vote</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/vote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/vote/</guid><description>Vote - a civic duty not to be taken for granted!</description></item><item><title>Common Projects</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/common-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/common-projects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lake Serene</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-serene/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-serene/</guid><description>The weather was a bit unpredictable this weekend, but we headed out to Lake Serene, an hour-and-a-half drive from the city. The GPS brought me to a private road and a dead end, and after several minutes of confusion and driving around, I finally headed to the right trailhead lot. Good to note, search for &amp;ldquo;Lake Serene Trailhead&amp;rdquo; and not just &amp;ldquo;Lake Serene.&amp;rdquo;
We arrived at around 1:15pm. The parking lot was packed, but the trail itself was fairly quiet.</description></item><item><title>Snoqualmie Falls</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/snoqualmie-falls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/snoqualmie-falls/</guid><description>This week went by pretty quickly. This weekend I wanted it to take it more low-key. Friday night and Saturday, aside from skating, I stayed indoors. The weather was a bit grey and gloomy, rainy too.
Earlier today, the weather cleared up slightly in the morning, and I even felt some sun and saw a patch of blue skies on my way to Snoqualmie Falls. Only 35 minutes outside the city, the Falls are more of a tourist attraction than a hike.</description></item><item><title>Lake 22</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-22/</guid><description>On this typical, Pacific Northwest rainy day, two of my friends and I decided to brave the rain and cold and head for a hike at Lake Twenty-Two. Only an hour or so drive from Seattle, the North Cascades are easily accessible from the city. We were told this hike was easy and flat, but we soon found out we were in for a nice surprise.
Stepping into this alpine wetland, looking up, I felt like we had entered an entirely different world and stepped into a prehistoric time capsule.</description></item><item><title>Arboretum</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/arboretum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/arboretum/</guid><description>After skating, shopping, and running errands, I drove to the Arboretum for an afternoon stroll before sunset. I parked at northern tip of the park and walked along the waterfront path. It had been raining earlier, but the sun started to break out of the clouds. At one point, a rainbow appeared too.
On this cozy fall afternoon, some went jogging along the muddy paths, some fishing in the lake, some just brining their dogs or kids out for a walk.</description></item><item><title>Month 1</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/month-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/month-1/</guid><description>Where does the time go?
One month in, and there&amp;rsquo;s still so much I want to get done. I&amp;rsquo;m getting better at driving, meeting new people and learning new things at work, and taking the time to explore my neighborhood and the city.
Saturday I headed to the rink once again and attempted more triples than I expected. I even landed a triple lutz-triple toe combo, not perfect, but rotated. Really, here, I&amp;rsquo;m relying all on muscle memory, from the thousands of repetitions I&amp;rsquo;ve engrained over the years.</description></item><item><title>Mount Rainier</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/mount-rainier/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/mount-rainier/</guid><description>After sleeping in, I convinced myself to go on a hiking adventure. I considered committing to an all-day trip to Rainier or a closer drive around Snoqualmie. The weather was decent so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a bet on heading into the mountains before winter (and the snow) hits. After some research online, I chose the Skyline Trail for the picturesque views. I refueled my car at Costco, picked up some cash and a lunch, and was on my way.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/hello-world/</guid><description>After circumnavigating the globe in less than 90 days, I landed back in the US longing to settle down, rest, and reflect on the wildest adventures that encompassed breathtaking hikes and waterfalls and last-minute food poisoning, snorkeling in the Pacific and witnessing kids fighting for their future.
With hundreds of gigabytes of photos and journal entires to look back on, I had to put that briefly on hold as I now embark on my next adventure: full-time, adult life.</description></item><item><title>What’s in a Name?</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/whats-in-a-name/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/whats-in-a-name/</guid><description>An Opportunity to Form Community and Forge a Sense of Belonging
Five weeks in, I’ve been getting better at remembering everyone’s name: the people on my team at OZÉ, the students I’m guest lecturing at the University of Ghana, and the local street vendors from whom I shop and purchase snacks and lunch. For example, there’s my co-worker Prince, a very unique but common name in Ghana; Mahfouz, who has roots in Mali and Togo; Kristen, who switches between her Ghanian and English name depending on who she is talking with; Janet, sometimes called Jane; Samuelle, a female but just as strong of a name as Samuel; and Rosalind and Rosa, sisters who share similar names who own adjacent shops.</description></item><item><title>What does Ghana, Hong Kong, and the US have in common?</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/post/what-does-ghana-hong-kong-and-the-us-have-in-common/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/what-does-ghana-hong-kong-and-the-us-have-in-common/</guid><description>“Where are you from?”
“The US.”
&amp;ldquo;You are a liar!&amp;rdquo; he shouted at me. The others jumped in. &amp;ldquo;You aren&amp;rsquo;t American! Just look at your face, your eyes, your hair!&amp;rdquo;
I was helping &amp;lsquo;storm&amp;rsquo; the local arts market in Accra, Ghana, with other sales reps at the startup I’m interning at. We were ready to leave when we met a group of shop owners near the entrance who were more curious about figuring out where exactly I was from.</description></item><item><title>Properties</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/properties/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 12:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/properties/</guid><description>COMING SOON...</description></item><item><title>Studio</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 12:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/studio/</guid><description>Shum+ is a design studio centered in the intersection of design and engineering — envisioning and developing the next-generation of user interactions01, interfaces02, and experiences03. More &amp;#x2197; -- MIT
MIT Media Lab ETH Zürich
Priceline.com
Credit Suisse
Accenture
MIT Consulting Group
Squarespace
-- 01 New Interactions MIT Media Lab / MIT / ETH Zürich -- MIT Media Lab MIT CSAIL MIT Engineering Interactive Technologies ETH Zürich 02 New Interfaces Credit Suisse / MIT / ETH Zürich -- Credit Suisse Priceline.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://kevinshum.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevinshum.com/about/</guid><description>-- asdf Services Blog Join Us -- -- Born in California, I've lived, worked, and traveled across 5 continents. I studied computer science and graduated with honours from MIT. I've developed next-generation human-computer interfaces and experiences in acaedmia, industry, and startups &amp;mdash; including the MIT Media Lab, CSAIL, and ETH Zürich. I've also worked on cloud computing at Microsoft. I'm a former Team USA figure skater and have two collegiate national titles.</description></item></channel></rss>