<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Kevin Shum</title>
	<subtitle>Seattle-based, MIT-trained design technologist, second-generation realtor &amp; former pro figure skater.</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://kevinshum.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://kevinshum.com/"/>
	<updated>2019-09-14T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
	<id>https://kevinshum.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Kevin Shum</name>
		<email>kevinshum@cbbain.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World!</title>
		<link href="https://kevinshum.com/posts/2019/helloworld/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-14T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://kevinshum.com/posts/2019/helloworld/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After circumnavigating the globe in less than 90 days, I landed back in the US longing to settle down, rest, and reflect on the wildest adventures that encompassed breathtaking hikes and waterfalls and last-minute food poisoning, snorkeling in the Pacific and witnessing kids fighting for their future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With hundreds of gigabytes of photos and journal entires to look back on, I had to put that briefly on hold as I now embark on my next adventure: full-time, adult life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is where this blog begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a student, there&#39;s freedom and excitement. Yet there&#39;s structure, a method to the madness. Each semester is 14 weeks long. We have 3 day weekends, Thanksgiving, Winter Break, Spring Break, summer holiday. Lectures, recitations, labs. Problem sets each week, midterms, exams. Then there&#39;s the next semester to look forward to, and the year after that. There&#39;s the goal of graduating, finding a job, working on that research project, finishing that pset, mastering that concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a full-timer, there&#39;s even greater freedom and excitement, yet more responsibility and independence. I&#39;m not sure what to expect, how I&#39;ll adapt to this new structure. Will I find a work-life balance? Will I keep up with the work items, finances, and my physical and mental health? What devote my free time to, in the evenings and weekends? How will I spend my limited time off? What do I have to look forward to? What&#39;s my next goal? How will I settle into a new city, a new group of friends and co-workers? What will my routines and rituals look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t imagine how I&#39;ll run out of things to do, places to explore, between settling into my new apartment, exploring the city, picking up new hobbies, meeting new people, learning on the job, making this place home, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is my hope to document this journey into adulthood, the uncertainty, anxieties, and excitement of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello world, indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>What does Ghana, Hong Kong, and the US have in common?</title>
		<link href="https://kevinshum.com/posts/2019/where-are-you-from/"/>
		<updated>2019-07-09T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://kevinshum.com/posts/2019/where-are-you-from/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Where are you from?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The US.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You are a liar!&amp;quot; he shouted at me. The others jumped in. &amp;quot;You aren&#39;t American! Just look at your face, your eyes, your hair!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was helping &#39;storm&#39; the local arts market in Accra, Ghana, with other sales reps at the startup I’m interning at. We were ready to leave when we met a group of shop owners near the entrance who were more curious about figuring out where exactly I was from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I was born in California,&amp;quot; I added, if that made my Americanness any more persuasive. To them, it didn’t matter where I was born. It was how I looked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my three weeks here, I&#39;ve lost track of the &amp;quot;ni hao&amp;quot; greetings I&#39;ve received on the streets. Sometimes it’s from kids not even 8 years old. On other occasions, I’m sitting in the backseat of an Uber in the middle of an intersection when a trotro (bus) driver looks at me and shouts, “Hey ching chong!”--twice. In any case, I usually respond with a polite hello and a smile, and walk away. Sometimes my American accent catches them off guard. Mandarin isn&#39;t even my mother tongue. In Cantonese--my first language--we say “hello,” a product of British rule of Hong Kong for over 150 years, or sometimes “nei5 hou2.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter where I go, I always feel slightly out of place. In the US, I&#39;m Asian. In Hong Kong, I’m American. At MIT, I’m from the Bay Area. Within my family, I’m Cantonese. Here in Ghana, I come from China. But because I’m always juggling multiple identities, expressed or assumed, I treat it as an opportunity to fluidly adapt to new cultures and environments I find myself in. So far, here in Ghana, I’m not only learning more about the diverse local traditions, identities, and histories that make this country unique--for example, the numerous local tribes, languages, and cultures, and the legacy of its colonial past--but about myself, and what it means to be Hong Kong-American in a completely different continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there are a lot more commonalities with Ghana and my own identities than I ever expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, let’s talk about food. Food is my favorite way to explore my own culture and new ones wherever I go, and Ghana is no exception. Since I arrived, my co-workers have been introducing me to new local street vendors. I’m trying new dishes every day: waakye, redred, jollof, palava, banku with tilapia, fried plantain, yams, and sweet potatoes, fufu with goat, fried rice, Indomie noodles, pawpaw smoothies, and much more. Banku reminds me of sourdough bread bowls unique to San Francisco. Fufu reminds me of mochi, my favorite dessert. Their take on fried rice and noodles seems to be inspired by similar dishes in Cantonese cuisine. Indomie noodles with sausage remind me of instant ramen with spam I loved as a kid. There’s even this hot pepper sauce called shito that reminds me of fish or shrimp paste used in other Asian dishes. The local Malta drink reminds me of the taste of traditional Chinese herbal jelly. Alvaro brings memories of Martinelli’s from California. Even the culture of street food is reminiscent of a similar culture in Hong Kong. In general, I’ve been surprised at the connections I can make with local dishes here with ones that I’ve grown up with that have become a part of my own identity. These new ingredients have not only excited my taste buds, but expanded my palette to encompass some of the diverse culinary traditions of Ghana and West Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kevinshum.com/img/Ghana/fufu.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Trying out fufu for the first time at a local food stand near the office. Fufu, to me, tastes like a savory version of mochi or sticky rice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the food, it’s been interesting to dive a bit deeper into the history of Ghana and draw parallels to those of my own identities. Both Hong Kong and Ghana (and the US) were former British colonies. I was born two days after the handover of Hong Kong on July 1, 1997. Here in Ghana, July 1st is Republic Day, the day Kwame Nkrumah became the country’s first president. Of course, we also celebrate the 4th of July back in the U.S. for our own independence. The most tangible impact of British colonial rule is that, even though these countries span three different continents, English is an official language in all three countries. But in Ghana and Hong Kong, the local languages blend in with British English. Here I’ve started to switch out “that’s right” or “you see?” with “aha,” as well as using “please” more often. I already say “ah” and “aiya” way too many times, and put “lah” at the end of my sentences, as Hongkongers like to do. We even use “aunty” in both countries to refer to a woman older and to show respect or deference. In Ghana, there’s Pidgin English; in Hong Kong, or whenever I converse with my parents, we often mix the two together and call it Chinglish or Kongish. “Okay, please,” perhaps I’ll carry with me some of the “small small” slang I’ve picked up here, “aha.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kevinshum.com/img/Ghana/apartment.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kevinshum.com/img/Ghana/apartmentview.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the neighborhood I’m living in this summer. Both Ghana and Hong Kong were former British colonies with tropical climates, and it’s been interesting to explore the commonalities in both countries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to get a deeper understanding of what makes Ghana unique and exciting, I’m learning more about myself and how my different identities fit within a global context. I’m no longer afraid of people asking me where I’m from. It’s only a superficial question. Where we’re from shouldn’t be the only thing that distinguishes us from one another; instead it should be an opportunity to engage in dialogue and uncover shared experiences that bring us closer together. Just in my short time here, I’ve found that we have more things in common than we might think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kevinshum.com/img/Ghana/relax.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Relaxing next to the beach in Accra, Ghana, on my day off. This area reminds me of the sea side beach towns with ocean views back home in California.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mistiblogs.com/2019/07/26/what-do-ghana-hong-kong-and-the-u-s-have-in-common&quot;&gt;MISTI Blogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
