<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fte on Kevin Shum</title>
    <link>https://kevinshum.com/tags/fte/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fte on Kevin Shum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Kevin Shum, &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Base Theme&lt;/a&gt;. </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevinshum.com/tags/fte/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake 22</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-22/</guid>
      <description>On this typical, Pacific Northwest rainy day, two of my friends and I decided to brave the rain and cold and head for a hike at Lake Twenty-Two. Only an hour or so drive from Seattle, the North Cascades are easily accessible from the city. We were told this hike was easy and flat, but we soon found out we were in for a nice surprise.
Stepping into this alpine wetland, looking up, I felt like we had entered an entirely different world and stepped into a prehistoric time capsule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/arboretum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/arboretum/</guid>
      <description>After skating, shopping, and running errands, I drove to the Arboretum for an afternoon stroll before sunset. I parked at northern tip of the park and walked along the waterfront path. It had been raining earlier, but the sun started to break out of the clouds. At one point, a rainbow appeared too.
On this cozy fall afternoon, some went jogging along the muddy paths, some fishing in the lake, some just brining their dogs or kids out for a walk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Rainier</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/mount-rainier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/mount-rainier/</guid>
      <description>After sleeping in, I convinced myself to go on a hiking adventure. I considered committing to an all-day trip to Rainier or a closer drive around Snoqualmie. The weather was decent so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a bet on heading into the mountains before winter (and the snow) hits. After some research online, I chose the Skyline Trail for the picturesque views. I refueled my car at Costco, picked up some cash and a lunch, and was on my way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>