<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kevin Shum</title>
    <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kevin Shum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Kevin Shum, &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Base Theme&lt;/a&gt;. </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 23:27:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevinshum.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Snoqualmie Falls</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/snoqualmie-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/snoqualmie-falls/</guid>
      <description>This week went by pretty quickly. This weekend I wanted it to take it more low-key. Friday night and Saturday, aside from skating, I stayed indoors. The weather was a bit grey and gloomy, rainy too.
Earlier today, the weather cleared up slightly in the morning, and I even felt some sun and saw a patch of blue skies on my way to Snoqualmie Falls. Only 35 minutes outside the city, the Falls are more of a tourist attraction than a hike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake 22</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/lake-22/</guid>
      <description>On this typical, Pacific Northwest rainy day, two of my friends and I decided to brave the rain and cold and head for a hike at Lake Twenty-Two. Only an hour or so drive from Seattle, the North Cascades are easily accessible from the city. We were told this hike was easy and flat, but we soon found out we were in for a nice surprise.
Stepping into this alpine wetland, looking up, I felt like we had entered an entirely different world and stepped into a prehistoric time capsule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/arboretum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/arboretum/</guid>
      <description>After skating, shopping, and running errands, I drove to the Arboretum for an afternoon stroll before sunset. I parked at northern tip of the park and walked along the waterfront path. It had been raining earlier, but the sun started to break out of the clouds. At one point, a rainbow appeared too.
On this cozy fall afternoon, some went jogging along the muddy paths, some fishing in the lake, some just brining their dogs or kids out for a walk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Month 1</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/month-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/month-1/</guid>
      <description>Where does the time go?
One month in, and there&amp;rsquo;s still so much I want to get done. I&amp;rsquo;m getting better at driving, meeting new people and learning new things at work, and taking the time to explore my neighborhood and the city.
Saturday I headed to the rink once again and attempted more triples than I expected. I even landed a triple lutz-triple toe combo, not perfect, but rotated. Really, here, I&amp;rsquo;m relying all on muscle memory, from the thousands of repetitions I&amp;rsquo;ve engrained over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Rainier</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/mount-rainier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/mount-rainier/</guid>
      <description>After sleeping in, I convinced myself to go on a hiking adventure. I considered committing to an all-day trip to Rainier or a closer drive around Snoqualmie. The weather was decent so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a bet on heading into the mountains before winter (and the snow) hits. After some research online, I chose the Skyline Trail for the picturesque views. I refueled my car at Costco, picked up some cash and a lunch, and was on my way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://kevinshum.com/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 23:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinshum.com/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>After circumnavigating the globe in less than 90 days, I landed back in the US longing to settle down, rest, and reflect on the wildest adventures that encompassed breathtaking hikes and waterfalls and last-minute food poisoning, snorkeling in the Pacific and witnessing kids fighting for their future.
With hundreds of gigabytes of photos and journal entires to look back on, I had to put that briefly on hold as I now embark on my next adventure: full-time, adult life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>